Finding Aid for S. Vern Taylor papers, 1833 and ca. 1860-1914
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
S. Vern Taylor papers
1833
circa 1860-1914
Taylor, S. Vern (Seneca Vern), 1887-1969.
8725 Aa 2; UAm
Graduate of the College of Engineering of the University of Michigan in the class of 1911, later Detroit businessman. Papers and photographs relating to student life and activities.
1 linear feet
1 oversize folders
1 oversize volumes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Mrs. Patricia Hoobler Schock (donor no. 5913 ) and came to the library in 1976.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
S. Vern Taylor graduated from the College of Engineering of the University of Michigan in 1911. He went on to become a successful Detroit businessman as president of the Concrete Steel Fireproofing Company.
The collection consists of programs and newspaper clippings largely concerning student life at the University of Michigan. The photographs are portraits and snapshots of Taylor, family members and friends; photographs of the construction of Barton Dam in Ann Arbor, Michigan; photographs of University of Michigan student surveying projects; and photographs of University of Michigan students, groups, and activities. In addition, there is an arithmetic notebook, 1833, of H. Green, student at the Detroit Academy. This item was probably collected by Taylor or perhaps in the possession of a family member.
Subjects:
Catholepistemiad (Detroit, Mich.); Engineering.; University of Michigan. College of Engineering.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1901-1910.StudentsSocial life and customs1901-1910.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1911-1920.StudentsSocial life and customs1911-1920.; Taylor, S. Vern (Seneca Vern), 1887-1969.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Aged persons.; Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.; Ann Arbor (Mich.); Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Streets.; Barton Dam (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Bridges.; Children.; Construction.; Dams.; Dwellings.; Engineering.; Families.; Fourteenth Avenue (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Golf.; Huron Street (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Interiors.; Laborers.; Michigan Union.; Postal service.; Secondhand sales.; Streets--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Surveying--Michigan.; Tau Beta Pi. Gamma Chapter (University of Michigan); Taylor, S. Vern (Seneca Vern), 1887-1969.; Taylor family.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Engineering. Class of 1911.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1901-1910.StudentsSocial life and customs1901-1910.; University of Michigan--Student housing--1901-1910.1901-1910.Student housing; Washington Street (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Women.; Women college students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Genre Terms:
Albums.; Photographs.; Postcards.; Tintypes.
- Papers
  - Undated (Box 1)
  - 1903-1907 (Box 1)
  - 1908 (Box 1)
  - 1909 (Box 1)
  - 1910 (Box 1)
  - 1911 (Box 1)
  - 1912-1914 (Box 1)
  - Arithmetic notebook of H. Green, student at Detroit Academy, 1833 (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Taylor, Seneca Vern. Portraits, snapshots (Box 1)
  - Taylor, Mrs. S.V. (?), with family (Box 1)
  - Barton Dam project: includes surveying, 1912 (Box 1)
  - Children (Box 1)
  - Groups, Family (Box 1)
    (see also oversize folder UAm)
  - Groups, Formal (Box 1)
  - Groups, School and Work; includes surveying (Box 1)
  - Groups, Social; includes Tau Beta Pi, golf (Box 1)
  - Groups, Other (Box 1)
  - Individuals, Men. Identified; includes J.B. Angell buying ticket for Union Circus (Box 1)
  - Individuals, Men. Unidentified (Box 1)
  - Individuals, Men. Unidentified; includes golf (Box 1)
  - Individuals, Women (Box 1)
  - Massena, N.Y. Project, 1913 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Tintypes, unidentified; 1 house, 4 group portraits, 1 individual portrait (Box 1)
  - University of Michigan photographs (Box 1)
  - Tau Beta Pi (Folder 1)
  - Taylor family (Folder 1)
  - University of Michigan College of Engineering, Class of 1911 (Folder 1)
  - Albums
    - Small album with New England literary figures, including: H.D. Thoreau, R.W. Emerson, A.B. Alcott, W.L. Garrison, Wendell Phillips, H.W. Beecher, George Duffield (Detroit minister) (Box 1)
    - Large album, of photos of unidentified family members, circa 1870-1900 (Box 1)
  - Atlas of student exercises, 1910 (Volume MH6/A613/1910/T246)
    (includes Stadia survey of vicinity east of Huron River between Cedar and Kellogg Streets; plane table survey of Michigan Union property; and map and camera survey of block east of Fireman's Park; all in Ann Arbor, Mich.; also includes 16 photographs of area east of Fireman's Park, Ann Arbor, Mich.)
    (atlas call no. MH6/A613/1910/T246)